https://www.ers.com/policy-pages/privacy-policy

About Us
One or more of ERS Syndicate Management Limited, ERS Syndicate Services Limited and ERS Administration Services Limited (“ERS” or “we”) are data controllers in respect of your personal information. Our registered office is at 21 Lombard Street, London, EC3V 9AH.
ERS Syndicate Management Limited (registered in England and Wales No. 426475) is Managing Agent of ERS Syndicate 218 at Lloyd’s and is authorised by the Prudential Regulation Authority and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority and the Prudential Regulation Authority, registered number 204851. ERS Syndicate Services Limited (registered in England and Wales No. 02661753) is an Appointed Representative (registered number 402561) of ERS Syndicate Management Limited and provides administrative services for ERS Syndicate Management Limited. ERS Administration Services Limited (registered in England and Wales No. 170558) is the main service company of the ERS Group and is the employing entity for all companies in the ERS Group.  All three companies are subsidiaries of ERS Insurance Group Limited, a Lloyd’s underwriting business (Syndicate 218) which has been a leading motor insurer for more than 70 years. More more information is available here
This privacy policy expands on the Data Protection Notice included in our policy documents. It describes the way in which we use your personal information and provides details of your rights. It contains important information so please make sure you read it carefully.
Introduction to the Insurance Market
Insurance involves the use and disclosure of your personal data by various insurance market participants such as intermediaries, insurers and reinsurers. The London Insurance Market Core Uses Information Notice sets out those core necessary personal data uses and disclosures. Our core uses and disclosures are consistent with the London Market Core Uses Information Notice. We recommend you review that notice as well as this privacy policy.
View LMA page here
View current version of the notice here
Who does this Privacy Policy apply to?
This privacy policy describes how we handle personal information about the following people:
People who request a quote, either directly or via a broker
Insurance policyholders
Named drivers and others covered by an ERS insurance policy
People who make a claim against one of our policyholders
Witnesses and other third parties whose information we may receive
We process personal information in line with the UK’s Data Protection laws and other relevant laws that apply.
The personal information we may collect about you
Types of Personal Data
Details
Individual details
Name, address (including proof of address), other contact details such as email and phone numbers, gender*, marital status, date and place of birth, nationality, employment status, job title, details of family members including their relationship to you
*This is used for identification purposes, demographic analysis, modelling and forecasting only Identification details
National insurance number, passport number, driving licence number,
other relevant licences
Financial information
Bank account and/or payment details, income and other financial
information
Risk details
Information to assess risk and provide insurance quotes, including
data relating to your health, disabilities and criminal convictions (including
motoring offences)
Policy information
Information about the quotes you receive and policies you take out
Telematics (if you use this technology)
Driving behaviour, location, frequency of vehicle use, time of use, mileage
Credit and anti-fraud information
Credit history, credit score, sanctions and criminal offences,
including information received from external databases about you
Previous and current claims
Information about previous and current claims (including under other insurance policies) which may include data relating to your health, disabilities, criminal convictions (including motoring offences) and in some cases surveillance reports; dashcam recordings where this technology is used; includes information about you from external databases and information collected from publicly available sources of information including social media.
Special categories of personal data
Information about health, disability, criminal convictions (including
motoring offences)
Where we collect your personal information
We may collect personal information about you from:
You
Your broker
Your family members
Your employer or their representative
Other companies in the insurance market, including providers of black box (telematics) services
Credit reference agencies
Anti-fraud databases, claims registers, sanctions lists, court judgement and similar databases
Government agencies such as the DVLA (to check licence and vehicle information) and HMRC
The publicly available electoral register
In the event of a claim, third parties including the other party to the claim, witnesses, experts, loss adjusters, legal advisers and claims handlers
Other publicly available sources of information including social media
How we use and disclose your personal information
Below is a summary of the different stages of the insurance relationship. Further details about how we use and disclose your personal information are set out in the subsequent sections of this privacy policy.
Quotation/Inception:
Setting you up as a client, including possible fraud, sanctions, credit and anti-money laundering checks
Evaluating the risks to be covered and matching to appropriate policy/premium
Payment of premium where the insured/policyholder is an individual
Policy administration:
Client care, including communicating with you and sending you updates
Payments to and from individuals
Telematics:
Determining driving behaviour and driving patterns
Developing flexible telematics rating models
Claims Processing:
Managing insurance and reinsurance claims
Defending or prosecuting legal claims
Investigating or prosecuting fraud
Renewals:
Contacting the insured/policyholder to renew the insurance policy
Evaluating the risks to be covered and matching to appropriate policy/ premium
Payment of premium where the insured/policyholder is an individual
Other purposes outside of the insurance lifecycle but necessary for the provision of insurance throughout the insurance lifecycle period:
Complying with our legal or regulatory obligations
General risk modelling and testing
Transferring books of business, company sales & reorganisations
The purchase by ERS of reinsurance coverage and reinsurance claims. This relates to large losses only
Disclosing and sharing your information:
To assess the terms of your insurance contract, or to deal with any claims, we may need to share information like your name, address, date of birth and details such as medical conditions or criminal convictions. The recipients of this information could include (but are not limited to) credit reference agencies, anti-fraud databases, other insurers, underwriters and other group companies who provide administration or support services. For claims handling, the recipients could include (but are not limited to) external claims handlers, loss adjusters, courts, legal and other expert advisers, and third parties who are involved in the claim. For reinsurance, recipients include reinsurance brokers, reinsurers and legal advisers. More information about these disclosures is set out below.
The Data Protection laws classify information about your medical conditions, disabilities and criminal convictions as ‘special category’ personal data which warrants extra protection. We will only share this kind of personal data where it is essential to administer your insurance contract or deal with any claims, or for anti-fraud purposes or for reinsurance matters.
Accepting and Administering Your Policy
If you pay your premiums via a credit facility, we may share your information with credit reference agencies and other companies for use in credit decisions, to prevent fraud and to find people who owe money. We share information with other insurers, certain government organisations and other authorised organisations. We may verify driving licence and vehicle information with the DVLA and may check No Claims records against an external database.
If you ask us to transfer your policy to another broker, we will disclose details of your policy (including any other people covered by the policy), any claims made and any other related information to the new broker at your request.
Insurance underwriting
We look at the possible risk in relation to your prospective policy (or anyone else involved in the policy) so that we can:
Consider whether to accept a risk;
Make decisions about providing and dealing with insurance and other related services for you and members of your household;
Set price levels for your policy;
Confirm your identity to prevent money laundering; and
Check the claims history for you or any person or property likely to be involved in the policy or a claim at any time. We may do this:
When you apply for or change your insurance;
If there is an accident or a claim; or
At the time you renew the policy.
Profiling
When calculating insurance premiums, we may compare your personal details against industry averages. Your personal information may also be used to create the industry averages going forwards. This is known as profiling and is used to ensure premiums reflect risk. Profiling may also be used to assess the information you provide so we can understand risk patterns.
Special categories of personal data may be used for profiling where this is relevant, such as medical history or past motoring convictions (including motoring offences). We may also make some decisions (for example about whether to offer cover or what the premiums will be) without any intervention by our staff. These are known as automated decisions. We rely on the information you provide to your broker and you can discuss the outcome of any automated decisions with your broker. See “Your Rights” below for further information.Motor Insurance Database
Information about your insurance policy will be added to the Motor Insurance Database (MID) which is managed by the Motor Insurers’ Bureau (MIB). Certain government or authorised organisations including the police, the DVLA, the DVLNI, the Insurance Fraud Bureau and other organisations allowed by law may use the MID and the information stored on it for purposes including:
Continuous Insurance Enforcement (you can get information about this from the Department of Transport);
Electronic vehicle licensing;
Law enforcement for the purposes of preventing, detecting, catching or prosecuting offenders; and
Providing government services or other services aimed at reducing the level of uninsured driving.
If you are involved in a road-traffic accident (either in the UK, the EEA or certain other territories), insurers or the MIB (or both) may search the MID to gather relevant information. Anyone making a claim for a road-traffic accident (including their appointed representatives and citizens of other countries) may also gather relevant information which is held on the MID.
It is vital that the MID holds your correct registration number. If it is not shown correctly on the MID, you are at risk of having your vehicle seized by the police. You can check that your correct registration number details are shown on the MID at www.askmid.com.You can find out more about how the MIB uses personal information here:
Managing claims
If you make a claim, we may need to release information to another person or organisation involved in that claim. This includes, but is not restricted to, your broker, your legal representative, others involved in the incident, their insurer, their solicitor or representative and medical teams, authorised repairers, the police or other investigators. We may have to investigate your current claim and your claim and conviction history. This may involve external claims handlers, loss adjusters, legal and other expert advisers.
Under the conditions of your policy, you must tell us about any incident (such as an accident or theft) which may or may not result in a claim. When you tell us about an incident, we will pass information relating to it to centrally managed claims registers which are operated on behalf of the insurance industry.
Call Recording
You should note that some telephone calls may be recorded or monitored, either by us, for example calls to or from our claims department, customer services team and underwriting department, or  on our behalf by our third party suppliers.  Call recording and monitoring may be carried out for the following purposes:
training and quality control;
as evidence of conversations; and/or
for the prevention or detection of crime (e.g. fraudulent claims).
Preventing or detecting fraud and other criminal offences
We will check your information against a range of registers and databases for completeness and accuracy. We may also conduct searches of publicly available sources of information including social media to verify claims and detect and prosecute fraud. We may share your information with law enforcement agencies, legal advisers, investigators, other organisations and public bodies.
If we find that false or inaccurate information has been given to us, or we suspect fraud, we will take appropriate action. If fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies including the Claims Underwriting Exchange (CUE), the Motor Insurance Anti-Fraud and Theft Register (MIAFTR) run by the Motor Insurance Bureau (MIB) and the Insurance Fraud Register (IFR) run by the Insurance Fraud Bureau. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information.
We and other organisations, including those from other countries, may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example, when:
Checking details on applications for credit and credit related or other facilities;
Managing credit and credit related accounts or facilities;
Recovering debt;
Checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance;
Checking details of job applicants and employees.
Details of the registers, databases and fraud prevention agencies we use may be requested from the Company Secretary at:
ERS Insurance Group Limited, 21 Lombard Street, London, EC3V 9AH.
Cheat line
To protect our policyholders, we are members of the Insurance Fraud Bureau (IFB). If you suspect insurance fraud is being committed, you can call them on their confidential cheat line on 0800 422 0421.
Consent and the Legal Basis for Processing Your Personal Information
Most of the personal information you provide to us is needed for us to assess your request for insurance, to enter into the insurance contract with you and then to administer that contract. Some of the information is collected for fraud prevention purposes, as described above.
If we need your consent to use any specific information, we will make that clear at the time we collect the information from you. You are free to withhold your consent or withdraw it at any time, but if you do so it may impact upon our ability to provide insurance or pay claims.
Further details about the legal basis for our processing of personal information, and the disclosures we may make, can be found in the Appendix below. Suppliers
Like most organisations, ERS uses a variety of companies to provide services on our behalf. We enter into contracts with those service providers to make sure they protect your personal information using appropriate security measures and we prohibit them from using your personal data other than as instructed by us.
Below is a list of service providers that have access to personal information to help service policies and subsequent claims:
Third Parties
Reason
Brokers
Brokers are the interface between ERS and policyholders. They
provide information to ERS about policyholders, named drivers and other
relevant individuals and we may share information with them about claims.
Some of our brokers are located in Jersey, Guernsey and/or Isle of Man.
Insurance Software Houses
Software houses operate a trading platform which brokers
can use to obtain quotations and insurance premiums for policies underwritten
by insurers such as ERS.
Fraud Organisations
We share data with fraud organisations to meet our
regulatory requirements and to protect ERS, our policyholders and claimants.
This includes various providers used to support pricing decisions.
Fraud Investigators
Where additional information is required in relation to a
reported or alleged incident, we may instruct claims investigators to carry
out additional services such as interviews, reports and evidence review in
order to validate the information presented. They need access to personal
details to conduct a thorough investigation.
Out of Hours Suppliers
These are contracted parties to handle claims notification
and indemnity enquiries outside of the ERS normal operating hours. They may have
remote access to ERS Policy and Claims systems.
Claims Suppliers (Repairers, Engineers, Salvage Agents,
Loss Adjusters, etc.)
These providers service claims as outlined in the
insurance policy. The third party will need access to personal details to
allow the claim to be reviewed and concluded.
Motor Insurance Bureau (MIB)
Motor Insurers have a regulatory requirement to submit
some personal information about policyholders to the Motor Insurance Database
(MID).
Administrative Support
ERS employs third party suppliers to manage inbound and
outbound correspondence (i.e. scanning, referencing post, cheque processing, printing
and postal services) and other administrative tasks. One of our
administrative support providers is located in India.
Document Management
Document storage, tape storage, document destruction.
Professional Advisers
Legal advisers, accountants, auditors, project managers
and other professional advisers.
IT and Related Providers
Software licenses/subscriptions, outsourced infrastructure
support, ERS insurance systems, payment platform providers, telephony
infrastructure and recordings.
Facilities
Cleaning and security services.
Reinsurance Brokers
Reinsurance Brokers are the interface between ERS and
reinsurers. We may share information with them regarding ERS’ policy summary
data and large losses specifically when dealing with reinsurance claims.
Reinsurers
Reinsurers provide reinsurance cover to ERS to protect
against material losses. This practice of spreading risk is standard practice
in the insurance market. They are provided with information regarding ERS’ policy
summary data only and large losses specifically when dealing with reinsurance
claims.
International Transfers
Some of the partner organisations and service providers we work with may be located in other countries. ERS uses service providers located in the USA, India and Israel. As a result, your information may be processed outside the European Economic Area. In all cases we will make sure that your information is adequately protected.
If you travel abroad, your information may need to be transferred to or from other countries in order to administer your insurance and deal with any claims, for example to provide recovery and repatriation services if your vehicle breaks down or you have an accident in another country.
Any other transfers of personal information outside Europe will be subject to the provisions of the US Privacy Shield, standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission or other contracts which provide equivalent protection.
Other Disclosures
In addition to the disclosures described elsewhere in this privacy policy, we may also disclose your personal information in the following circumstances: (i) if required by law; (ii) in connection with a reorganisation, sale or transfer of all or any part of our business; (iii) if we believe that the disclosure is necessary to enforce or apply the terms of our contracts or otherwise to exercise or defend our rights; (iv) in order to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order or other legal obligation, or a regulatory or government inquiry.
Retention
We will keep your personal data only for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. In particular, we will retain your information for as long as there is any possibility that either you or we may wish to bring a legal claim under or relating to your insurance, or where we are required to keep your information for legal or regulatory purposes. We have various different retention periods for different types of claims and other records. If you would like more information about this, please contact us at the address shown below.
We may keep anonymised data for longer periods for analysis and modelling purposes.
Your Rights
You have rights under the Data Protection laws including the right to access the information we hold about you and receive a copy of that information (subject to any legal restrictions that may apply), to have the information corrected if it is inaccurate, and to have it updated if it is incomplete.
You can also find out about any automated decisions we make that affect your insurance or premiums.
We may ask for proof of your identity before we can respond to your request.
We will ask your permission before carrying out any marketing. You have the right to opt out of receiving marketing at any time. You can use the unsubscribe option that is included in all our marketing emails or contact us using the details given below.
In very limited circumstances and only where you have given us your express consent, we may pass your data to a third party so that they can contact you for marketing purposes. In such circumstances we will act as data processor in collecting your consent and sending it to the third party, and the third party will be the data controller in respect of the relevant data. You should refer to the relevant third party’s privacy policy for further information on how they use your data.
In certain circumstances you may also have the following rights:
The right to have your data deleted;
The right to restrict or object to the processing of your personal data;
Where you have provided personal data voluntarily, or otherwise consented to its use, the right to withdraw your consent;
The right to receive a copy of the personal information which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format or to request that we transfer that information to another party (known as “data portability”).
If you wish to exercise any of your rights, please contact us at:
Data Protection Officer
ERS
21 Lombard Street
London
EC3V 9AH
dpo@ers.com
If you are not satisfied with our use of your personal data or our response to any request by you to exercise your rights in relation to your personal data, please contact compliance@ers.com
You also have a right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner:
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
SK9 5AF
Tel: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545745 (national rate)
Email: casework@ico.org.uk
Appendix – Legal Basis for Processing Personal Information PURPOSE
Categories of data
Legal grounds
Disclosures
QUOTATION/INCEPTION
Setting you up as a client, including
fraud, credit and anti-money laundering and sanctions checks
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Financial information
Personal data:
• Performance of our contract with you
• Compliance with a legal obligation
• Legitimate interests (to ensure that
the client is within our acceptable risk profile)
• Group companies providing administration
• Credit reference agencies
• Anti-fraud databases
Special categories of personal data:
• Credit and anti-fraud data
Special categories of personal data:
• In the substantial public interest
• Consent
QUOTATION/INCEPTION
Evaluating the risks to be covered
& matching to appropriate policy/premium
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Perform contract
• Legitimate interests (to determine
the likely risk profile and appropriate insurance product and premium)
Special categories of personal
data:
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Credit and anti-fraud data
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
QUOTATION/INCEPTION
and POLICY ADMINISTRATION
Collection or refunding of Premium
• Individual details
• Financial information
• Perform contract
• Legitimate interests (to recover
debts due to us)
Banks
MARKETING
Personal data:
marketing
preferences (opt in/opt out)
Consent
Group companies
providing administration;
Third parties
in respect of other insurance products
POLICY ADMINISTRATION
General client care, including
communicating with you regarding administration and requested changes to the
insurance policy. Sending you updates regarding your insurance policy.
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Perform contract
• Legitimate interests (to correspond
with clients, beneficiaries and claimants in order to facilitate placing of
and claims under insurance policies)
Special categories of personal data:
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
Consent
CLAIMS PROCESSING
Managing insurance claims including
fraud, credit and anti-money laundering and sanctions checks
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Financial information
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Perform contract
• Legitimate interests (to assess the
veracity and quantum of claims)
• Claims handlers
• Solicitors
• Loss adjustors
• Experts
• Third parties involved in the claim
Special categories of personal data:
• Credit and anti-fraud data
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
• Legal claims
CLAIMS PROCESSING
Defending or prosecuting legal claims
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Financial information
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Perform contract
• Legitimate interests (to defend or
make claims)
• Claims handlers
• Solicitors
• Loss adjustors
• Experts
• Third parties involved in the claim
Special categories of personal data:
• Credit and anti-fraud data
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
• Legal Claims
CLAIMS PROCESSING
Investigating & prosecuting fraud
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Financial information
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Perform contract
• Legitimate interests (to assist with
the prevention and detection of fraud)
• Solicitors
• Private Investigators
• Police
• Experts
• Third parties involved in the
investigation or prosecution
• Other insurers
• Anti-fraud databases
Special categories of personal data:
• Health data
• Criminal records data
• Other sensitive data
• Credit and anti-fraud data
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
• Legal claims
• Substantial Public Interest
RENEWALS
Contacting you in order to renew the
insurance policy
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Perform contract
• Legitimate interests (to correspond
with clients, beneficiaries and claimants in order to facilitate the placing
of and claims under insurance policies)
Special categories of personal data:
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
THROUGHOUT THE INSURANCE LIFECYCLE
Transferring books of business,
company sales and reorganisations
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Financial information
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Legitimate interests (to structure
our business appropriately)
• Legal obligation
• Courts
• Purchaser
Special categories of personal data:
• Credit and anti-fraud data
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
• Substantial Public Interest
THROUGHOUT THE INSURANCE LIFECYCLE
General risk modelling & underwriting
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Financial information
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Legitimate interests (to build risk
models that allow accepting of risk with appropriate premiums)
Special categories of personal data:
• Credit and anti-fraud data
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
Substantial public interest
REINSURANCE
managing reinsurance claims
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Legitimate interests (to ensure we
have appropriate insurance in place from reinsurers and to make claims under
the reinsurance policies)
Reinsurance brokers, reinsurers and
advisers.
Special categories of personal data:
Medical data
Special categories of personal data:
• Substantial public interest (use of
the data is necessary for insurance purposes)
• Legal Claims
THROUGHOUT THE INSURANCE LIFECYCLE
Complying with our legal or regulatory
obligations
Personal data:
• Individual details
• Identification details
• Financial information
• Policy information
Personal data:
• Legal obligation
• PRA, FCA, ICO and other regulators
• Police
• Other insurers (under court order)
Special categories of personal data:
• Credit and anti-fraud data
• Risk Details
• Previous claims
• Current claims
Special categories of personal data:
• Consent
• Substantial Public Interest
For Brokers
About Us
ERS Syndicate Management Limited and ERS Administration Services Limited (“ERS” or “we”) are data controllers in respect of your personal information.
ERS Insurance Group Limited is the holding company of the ERS Group  in the Lloyd’s market (Syndicate 218) as a motor insurer for more than 70 years. Subsidiary companies include ERS Syndicate Management Limited (registered in England and Wales No. 426475), a managing agent which is authorised by the Prudential Regulation Authority (registered number 204851) and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority ; and ERS Administration Services Limited (registered in England and Wales No. 170558), which provides services to the managing agent. , For more information, please visit ers.com
This privacy policy describes the way in which we use your personal information and provides details of your rights. It contains important information so please make sure you read it carefully.
Who does this Privacy Policy apply to?
ERS is committed to protecting your personal information.  This privacy policy relates to the personal information we collect in relation to individuals (“you”, “your”) who are employed by, work for, manage or own broker companies who conduct business with us (“Company”).
This privacy policy applies where you interact with ERS by e-mail, by telephony, in writing, in person or through our online services..  A separate ERS privacy policy www.ers.com/policy-pages/priva... governs the way in which ERS collects and uses personal information relating to your customers.
This privacy policy should be read in conjunction with the Terms of Business Agreement (“TOBA”) which ERS Syndicate Management Limited has in place with your Company.
The personal information we may collect about you
Types of Personal Data
Details
Individual
details
Name, address, other contact details such as email
address and phone numbers, job title and role, image.
If you are a director or partner of your company, we
will collect information about your date of birth, national insurance number
and current and previous three years’ addresses.
Account
registration details
Username,
passwords.
Marketing
preferences
Opt-in/Opt-out
Where we collect your personal information
We may collect personal information about you when:
You or your company does business with us
You register for or use our online services
You register for our newsletter
You participate in any ERS broker competitions
You contact or communicate with us  - you should note that some telephone calls may be recorded or monitored for the following purposes:Training and quality controlAs evidence of conversationsHow we use and disclose your personal information and our legal basis for doing so:
Legal basis: Necessary to enter into or fulfil ERS’ obligations under the contract between us, or otherwise necessary for ERS’s legitimate business needs consistent with the TOBA we have in place with you and in the interest of providing an efficient service to you and your customers:
Set up an account
Maintain that account
Allow you to access and make use of ERS online services
Administer and manage products that your customers have with us
Manage quotations, enquiries, queries and complaints
Carry out necessary background checks to make sure you are a legitimate person to do business with
To market our products and services – we will use your personal information to keep you informed about our products and services subject to your marketing preferences.
To make improvements to our operations – we will use your personal information for research and statistical purposes to analyse how brokers use our website, our products and other services so we can improve our understanding of user needs and enhance our products.
To meet the responsibilities we have to our regulators, tax officials, law enforcement or otherwise meet our legal responsibilities – if you are a director or partner of your Company   we will carry our appropriate verification and credit checks.  We use personal information for these purposes to comply with requirements we have under financial conduct rules and laws relating to anti-money laundering, financial crime and to prevent and detect fraud
Where we have obtained appropriate consents from you – to collect or use your personal information for a particular purpose.  This will always be explained to you separately when we ask for your consent.  If we need your consent to use any specific information, we will make that clear at the time we collect the information from you. You are free to withhold your consent or withdraw it at any time
Legal basis: Necessary for our legitimate business interests to develop, enhance and promote the products and services we provide:
Legal basis: Necessary for compliance with ERS’s legal responsibilities:
Legal basis: With your consent:
If you would like to know more about any of the above that apply to a particular way in which we use personal information you can contact us at any time www.ers.com/contact
Use of third party information
We obtain information about you from third party service providers and databases for assurance purposes.  Below is a list of third party service providers from whom we obtain information about you  to help us provide our services:
Third Parties
Reason
Credit check companies
In order to do business with yourselves we will run a
credit score report which will show your financial behaviour over the last
few years to help us decide whether to give you credit.
Insurance Software Houses
Software houses operating a trading platform between us
and you to obtain quotations and insurance premiums for policies underwritten
by insurers such as ERS.
Disclosing and sharing your information
If you request a quote, or purchase a product on behalf of your customer, information about you and your company may be shared with and processed by our Third Party Service Providers who help us facilitate the administration of our business.  We enter into contracts with those service providers to make sure they protect you and your customers’ personal information using appropriate security measures.  Below is a list of service providers that have access to personal information to help us to provide our products and services;
Third Parties
Reason
Fraud Organisations
We share data with fraud organisations to meet our
regulatory requirements and to protect ERS, our policyholders and claimants.
This includes various providers used to support pricing decisions.
Out of Hours Suppliers
These are contracted parties to handle claims
notification and indemnity enquiries outside of the ERS normal operating
hours. They may have remote access to ERS Policy and Claims systems.
Motor Insurance Bureau (MIB)
Motor Insurers have a regulatory requirement to submit
some personal information about policyholders to the Motor Insurance Database
(MID).
Administrative Support
ERS employs third party service providers to manage
inbound and outbound correspondence (i.e. scanning, referencing post, cheque
processing, printing and postal services) and other administrative tasks. One
of our administrative support providers is located in India.
Document Management
Document storage, tape storage, document destruction.
Professional Advisers
Legal advisers, accountants, auditors, project managers
and other professional advisers.
IT and Related Providers
Software licenses/subscriptions, outsourced
infrastructure support, ERS insurance systems, payment platform providers,
telephony infrastructure and recordings.
For further details regarding how we share information related to our products on behalf of your customer, please visit our privacy policy at www.ers.com
We may also share information about you with:
Our regulators and law enforcement bodies as necessary for purposes of fraud prevention and detection and legal or regulatory requirements
Your customers if they have queries about the services between you, them and us.
Our social media for competitions where we may publish names, images and company name of winners.
Marketing and Cookies
To protect your privacy rights and your choice and control over the use of your personal information, we will always allow you the opportunity to opt-out of marketing communications when you register your contact information with us. In addition, you can always ‘opt out’ of receiving direct marketing by using the unsubscribe links you will find on our marketing emails. You can also change your marketing preferences in the Broker preference centre in the profile settings of your online account at any time.
We rely on third-party advertising technology (such as the deployment of cookies or small text files on our website) to collect information about you, which is used to optimise what you may see on our websites and deliver content when you are browsing elsewhere. We may also collect information about your use of other websites. We do this to provide you with advertising that we believe may be relevant for you, as well as to improve our own products and services.
Our
online advertising complies with the best practice recommendation set by
the European Advertising Alliance and you will always see the blue logo on
display ads visible on third-party sites.
You
can turn off this type of advertising by visiting youronlinechoices.com
and adjusting privacy settings in your browser.
If
we use or share information with online sources, such as websites, social
media and information sharing platforms, we will respect any permissions
you have set about how you would like your personal information to be
used.
If
you choose to opt out of tailored offers and advertising, you’ll still
continue to see generic advertising displayed online, it just might not be
as relevant to you.Fraud Prevention and DetectionIn order to prevent and detect fraud we may at any time:
Share information about you with other organisations and public bodies including the Police;Undertake credit searches and additional fraud searches;Check and/or file your details with fraud prevention agencies and databases, and if you give us false or inaccurate information and we suspect fraud, we will record this to prevent fraud and money laundering.We can supply, on request, further details of the agencies and databases we access or contribute to and how this information may be used. If you require further details contact our Data Protection Officer at ERS, 21 Lombard Street
London EC3V9AH or dpo@ers.com.
We and other organisations may also search these agencies and databases to:
Help make decisions about the provision and administration of insurance, credit and related servicesTrace debtors or beneficiaries, recover debt, prevent fraudCheck your identity to prevent money laundering, unless you furnish us with other satisfactory proof of identityAny requests for information we receive from law enforcement bodies or regulators will be carefully validated before any personal information is disclosed.
International Transfers
Some of the organisations we share information with may be located outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA"). We’ll always take steps to ensure that any transfer of information outside the EEA is carefully managed to protect your privacy rights. We will only transfer personal information to countries which are recognised as providing an adequate level of legal protection or where we can be satisfied that alternative arrangements are in place to protect your privacy rights.
Where we transfer your data to third parties providing us with a service, we will obtain contractual commitments and assurances from them to protect your personal information. Some of these assurances include the standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission and recognised certification schemes such as the EU - U.S. Privacy Shield for the protection of personal information transferred from within the EU to the United States of America.
Retention
We will keep your personal data only for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which it was collected. In particular, where we are required to keep your information for legal or regulatory purposes.  We have various different retention periods for different types of information and records. If you would like more information about this, please contact us at the address shown below.
Your Rights
You have rights under the Data Protection Act including the right to access the information we hold about you and receive a copy of that information (subject to any legal restrictions that may apply), to have the information corrected if it is inaccurate, and to have it updated if it is incomplete.
We may ask for proof of your identity before we can respond to your request.
You have the right to opt out of receiving marketing at any time. You can use the unsubscribe option that is included in all our marketing emails or contact us using the details given below.
In certain circumstances you may also have the following rights:
The right to have your data deleted
The right to restrict or object to the processing of your personal data
Where you have provided personal data voluntarily, or otherwise consented to its use, the right to withdraw your consent
The right to receive a copy of the personal information which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format or to request that we transfer that information to another party (known as “data portability”)
If you wish to exercise any of your rights, please contact us at:
dpo@ers.com or write to David Turner at ERS, 21 Lombard Street
London EC3V9AH
Changes to this Privacy Policy
We may amend this privacy policy from time to time, for example to keep it up to date or to comply with legal requirements. You should regularly check this privacy policy for updates. If there will be any significant changes made to the use of your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you by posting a notice on www.ers.com.
Contact usIf you have any questions about this privacy policy or how to exercise your rights please contact our Data Protection Officer.
Write to:
David Turner
ERS
21 Lombard Street
London
EC3V9AH
Email us: dpo@ers.com
Your right to complainIf you are not satisfied with our use of your personal information, you have a right to make a complaint to your local data protection supervisory authority at any time. In the UK this is the Information Commissioners Office. (www.ico.org.uk)
We ask that you please attempt to resolve any issues with us before contacting the ICO.
Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
SK9 5AF
Tel: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545745 (national rate)
Email: casework@ico.org.uk
About
Careers
Privacy Policy
Terms and Conditions
Cookie Policy
Modern Slavery Act
© 2020 ERS Insurance
ERS, syndicate 218 at Lloyd's, is managed by ERS Syndicate Management Limited (registered number 426475) which is authorised by the Prudential Regulation Authority and regulated by Prudential Regulation Authority and the Financial Conduct Authority (FRN 204851). Registered office 21 Lombard Street, London EC3V 9AH.
